Register to the Papers of Kurt Weill and Lotte Lenya
Yale University Music Library
- Loose Clippings, 1926-1982; Series XIII; 4.2' (10 boxes)
  - Lenya's Concert Performances of Weill's Works, XIII.D
    - Carnegie Hall concerts, 1959-1965; 62 items. (Box 90, Folder 95)
    - Curtis Institute of Music, 1976; 6 items. (Box 90, Folder 96)
    - Wayne State University, 1980; 8 items. (Box 90, Folder 97)
  - Stage Performances by Lenya, XIII.E
    - Barefoot In Athens (Anderson), 1951; 24 items. (Box 91, Folder 98)
    - Brecht on Brecht, 1962-1973; 156 items. (Box 91, Folder 99-100)
    - Cabaret, 1966-1975; 57 items. (Box 91, Folder 101)
    - Candle in the Wind (Anderson), 1941-1942; 49 items. (Box 91, Folder 102)
    - Mutter Courage (Brecht), 1963-1978; 53 items. (Box 91, Folder 103)
  - Television/Radio Performances or Interviews with Lenya, XIII.F
    - "Camera Three", 1958; 2 items. (Box 91, Folder 104)
    - "Lotte Lenya: The Broadway Years of Kurt Weill" (Stage 2), 1964; 20 items. (Box 91, Folder 105)
    - "The World of Kurt Weill", 1966-1967; 5 items. (Box 91, Folder 106)
    - "Interregnum", 1966; 2 items.
    - Ten Blocks on the Camino Real (Tennessee Williams), 1966; 2 items.
    - "Theater in Exile", 1973; 3 items. (Box 91, Folder 107)
    - Today-Show, 1975; 1 item.
    - "Show" (Wien), 1975; I items.
    - Dick Cavett Show, 1975-1976; 3 items.
    - "New York, New York" (Werner Baecker), 1978 Nov. 13; 1 item. (Box 91, Folder 108)
    - "Lenya: The Berlin Years" (Skyline), 1979; 8 items.
    - Lotte Lenya/Nancy Shear Interview, 1979 May 4; 1 item.
    - Lotte Lenya/Klaus Figge/Gottfried Wagner interview, 1979; 3 items.
    - "Omnibus" (BBC), 1979; 16 items. (Box 91, Folder 109)
    - Lenya/Werner Baecker interview, 1979; 4 items.
  - Lenya in Films, XIII.G
    - From Russia with Love, 1964-1977; 9 items. (Box 91, Folder 110)
    - The Roman spring of Mrs. Stone, 1961-1972; 16 items. (Box 91, Folder 111)
    - Semi-Tough, 1976-1978; 7 items. (Box 91, Folder 112)
  - Miscellaneous Clippings, XIII.H
    - Re Brecht, 1959-1981; 36 items. (Box 91, Folder 113)
    - Miscellaneous articles including some re friends, 1942-1981; 178 items. (Box 91; 92, Folder 114; 115-116)
    - Negatives of nine articles, 1926-1933; 9 items. (Box 92, Folder 117)
- Clippings from Anna Krebs's Scrapbooks, 1930-1964; Series XIV; 2.5' (6 boxes)
  Clipping service clippings from scrapbooks belonging to Anna Krebs, a close friend of Lenya's, are arranged chronologically within the title of show or subject entry.
  - Works by Weill, XIV.A
    - Antigonemodell, 1963 Jul. 5; 1 item. (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Aufstieg und Fall der Stadt Mahagonny, 1930-1964; 972 items. (Box 93; 94, Folder 2-8; 9-11)
      See also: Street scene (ca. 1979) and Gerhard Lenssen.
    - Das Berliner Requiem, 1963 Jul. 13; 1 item. (Box 94, Folder 12)
      - Der brave Soldat Schwejk, 1960-1961; 3 items.
    - Die Bürgschaft, 1957-1962; 9 items. (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Concerto, violin, 1960-1962; 19 items. (Box 94, Folder 14)
    - Down in the Valley, 1957-1962; 62 items. (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - Die Dreigroschenoper, 1955-1964; 815 items. (Box 94; 95, Folder 16-20; 21-24)
      See also: Die sieben Todsünden (1960 Mar. 9), and Gerhard Lenssen.
    - The Eternal Road, 1961; 1 item. (Box 95, Folder 25)
    - Frauentanz, 1962; 3 items. (Box 95, Folder 26)
    - Happy End, 1960-1963; 41 items. (Box 95, Folder 27)
    - Der Jasager, 1930-1964; 17 items. (Box 95, Folder 28)
    - Johnny Johnson, 1956 May 16; 1 item. (Box 95, Folder 29)
    - Kleine Dreigroschenmusik, 1961-1964; 7 items. (Box 95, Folder 30)
      See also: Mahagonny.
    - Knickerbocker Holiday, 1961-1964; 12 items. (Box 95, Folder 31)
    - Der Lindberghflug, 1962-1963; 7 items. (Box 95, Folder 32)
    - Lost in the Stars, 1961-1964; 372 items. (Box 95, Folder 33-36)
    - Love Life, 1963 Nov. 23; 1 item. (Box 96, Folder 37)
    - Mahagonny, 1960-1963; 101 items. (Box 96, Folder 38-39)
      See also: Happy End.
    - Der neue Orpheus, 1960 Feb. 3; 1 item. (Box 96, Folder 40)
    - One Touch of Venus, 1962 Nov.; 1 item. (Box 96, Folder 41)
    - Der Protagonist, 1961 Jul. 8; 1 item. (Box 96, Folder 42)
      See also: Die sieben Todsünden (1960 Mar.).
    - Die sieben Todsünden, 1956-1973; 731 items. (Box 96, Folder 43-49)
    - Der Silbersee, 1960; 4 items. (Box 97, Folder 50)
      See also: Street Scene (ca. 1979).
    - Street Scene, 1961-1963; 5 items. (Box 97, Folder 51)
    - Der Zar lässt sich photographieren, 1960-1963; 45 items. (Box 97, Folder 52)
      See also: Die sieben Todsünden (ca. 1960 Mar.).
    - Gerhard Lenssen's Brecht/Weill one-man show, 1959-1964; 138 items. (Box 97, Folder 53)
    - Musika-Viva-Konzert (München) With Lenya., 1960; 47 items. (Box 97, Folder 54)
    - Kranichsteiner Musikinstitut (Darmstadt), 1960; 4 items. (Box 97, Folder 55)
      With Lenya.
    - Berlin Akademie der Künste, 1960; 115 items. (Box 97, Folder 56)
    - Berlin Festwochen, 1961; 4 items. (Box 97, Folder 57)
    - Performances by Lenya of miscellaneous works by Kurt Weill, 1930-1963; 10 items. (Box 97, Folder 58)
    - Performances by others of miscellaneous works by Kurt Weill, 1960-1964; 47 items. (Box 97, Folder 59)
  - Recordings and Books, XIV.B
    - Recordings of two or more works by Kurt Weill - by Lenya, 1956-1964; 19 items. (Box 97, Folder 60)
    - Recordings of two or more works by Kurt Weill - by Others, 1958-1964; 47 items. (Box 97, Folder 61)
    - Lenya reading German poetry, 1958-1963; 18 items. (Box 97, Folder 62)
    - Books re Kurt Weill and Lenya, 1960-1964; 34 items. (Box 97, Folder 63)
    - Dreigroschenbuch (Brecht), 1960-1963; 26 items. (Box 97, Folder 64)
  - General Articles about Weill and Lenya, XIV.C
    - Weill, 1956-1964; 88 items. (Box 97, Folder 65)
    - Re the 10th anniversary of Kurt Weill's death, 1960; 88 items. (Box 97, Folder 66)
    - Lenya, 1955-1973; 94 items. (Box 98, Folder 67)
    - Lenya/Detwiler marriage, 1962-1963; 188 items. (Box 98, Folder 68)
  - Lenya on Stage and Film, XIV.D1
    - Baal (Brecht), 1963; 137 items. (Box 98, Folder 69)
      - Brecht on Brecht, 1962-1963
    - Roman Spring of Mrs. Stone, 1961-1963; 293 items. (Box 98, Folder 70-71)
    - From Russia with Love, 1964; 1 item. (Box 98, Folder 72)
  - Lenya on Television, XIV.D2
    - Interregnum, 1961-1962; 7 items. (Box 98, Folder 73)
    - German TV interviews, 1961-1962; 18 items. (Box 98, Folder 74)
    - "Die Welt Kurt Weills", 1963-1964; 10 items. (Box 98, Folder 75)
  - Miscellaneous, XIV.E
    - Friends including Kaiser and Brecht, 1930-1964; 28 items. (Box 98, Folder 76)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1958-1962; 15 items. (Box 98, Folder 77)
- Miscellaneous Items, 1890-1984; Series XV; .4' (1 box)
  Miscellaneous items are arranged chronologically within entries grouped by type of item.
  - Der synagogale Gesang... / von Dr. A. Ackermann, Ackermann, A.; 1 item; 53 p.; 22 cm. (Box 99, Folder 1)
    Trier: Sigmund Mayer, 1984.
  - Hagada, 63 p.; 19 cm.
    Frankfurt a. M.: J. Kauffmann, 1890.
  - Jottings by Lenya and others, 33 items. (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Lists of songs, exhibit items, and tour schedules, 1972-1978; 6 items. (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Membership cards belonging to Kurt Weill, Lenya, and Russell Detwiler, 1946-1978; 6 items. (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Business cards, n.d.; 6 items. (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Sketches and prints, 20 items. (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Blank postcards, n.d.; 59 items. (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Invitations, 1935-1979; 11 items. (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1935-1977 (Box 99, Folder 8-9)
- Kurt Weill Conference Items, 1983-1984; Series XVI; .8' (2 boxes)
  Items related to the Kurt Weill Conference held at Yale University, November 2-5, 1983.
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984; 5 items. (Box 100, Folder 1)
    Two photographs laid in.
  - Clippings, 1983-1984; 30 items. (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1983 Oct.-Nov.; 6 items. (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - Kurt Weill Newsletter, 1983-1984; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Registration packet for the conference, 1983; 20 items. (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Kurt Weill... - Leipzig: VEB Deutscher Verlag für Musik, 1983; Schebera, Jurgen; 1 item; 350 p.; 22 cm. (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Bronze medallion commemorating the conference by Markika Somogyi and Mel Wacks (2 copies), 1983; 2 items. (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - Posters, 1983; 2 items. (Box 107, Folder 4)